# Sithum Sandaruwan

sithumsandaruwan200123@gmail.com

+94769435948

linkedin.com/in/sithum-sandaruwan

## **Summary**

As a software engineering student at the Institute of Computer Engineering Technology (iCET), learning advanced skills in Java, MySQL and software development. I am also pursuing my Certified Master Diploma from iCET.I have a completed first semester diploma in software engineering from IJSE and a diploma in English from ICBT.

As a member of Generation ALPHA,I developed my communication skills ,personal branding & teamwork .Which have helped me improve my communication and problem-solving abilities.

I have also gained practical experience as a trainee at Metro Computers Technology, A leading company in computer hardware and software solutions in Matara. There, I worked on various projects involving hardware installation, troubleshooting, maintenance and repair. And I completed NVQ Level 4 Computer Hardware Technician Course in Technical College, Matara.

I have completed multiple certifications from LinkedIn on generative AI, including one on how it can enhance online search and another on how to streamline work with Copilot, a generative AI-powered chatbot.

My goal is to become a proficient and versatile software engineer and Proceed through it.

# **Experience**



#### Member

Generation ALPHA 2023 - Present (1 year)

#### Intern

Metro Computers Technology Nov 2021 - Jun 2022 (8 months)

### **Education**

# Institute of Computer Engineering Technology (iCET)

iCET Certified Master Programme (iCM 107 Batch), Computer Software Engineering Nov 2023 - Present

# Institute of Java & Software Engineering(IJSE), Gries Peris Road, Panadura.

Graduate Diploma in Software Engineering (GDSE 67 Batch), Computer Software Engineering

Apr 2023 - Oct 2023



### 🌠 St. Thomas' College, Matara.

2006 - 2020

### Technical College, Matara.

Computer Hardware Technician NVQ 4, Computer Hardware Technology/Technician

### ICBT Campus

Diploma In English, English Language and Literature, General

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- in What Is Generative AI? LinkedIn
- Generative AI: The Evolution of Thoughtful Online Search LinkedIn
- Streamlining Your Work with Copilot (formerly Bing Chat/Bing Chat Enterprise) -LinkedIn
- Introduction to Career Skills in Software Development LinkedIn
- in Learning Microsoft 365 Copilot LinkedIn
- **Ethics in the Age of Generative AI** LinkedIn
- Programming Foundations: Fundamentals LinkedIn

### **Skills**

Project Planning • Community Development • Strategic Communications • HTML • Computer Repair • Computer Networking • Computer Maintenance • Teamwork • Interpersonal Communication • English